mygalottery.com 2017-01-28

# Georgia Lottery - Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the websites (" **Websites** ") and/or downloading the mobile application ("Mobile Application" and collectively with the Websites, the " **Sites** " or the " **Site** ") operated by or on behalf of the Georgia Lottery Corporation (herein " **we** " or " **us** "). This Privacy Policy (" **Policy** ") explains the digital information practices of the Georgia Lottery Corporation and sets out what information we collect through the Sites, how we collect it, and what we do with it. Additionally, we may post this Policy with any other application or software authorized by us to access and/or display our Products from time to time, in which case the subject application or software shall also be considered a "Site" for purposes hereof. Please contact us as indicated in the " **Contact Us** " section below if you have any questions or would like additional information. We may update this Policy from time to time, so please check this Policy periodically for changes.

### Your Information

We may collect non-public, personal information when you use this Site or when you communicate with us through this Site. We define "personal information" as information that is unique to an individual and might include the following alone or in some combination: name, date of birth, mailing address, zip code, other contact information, billing information, email addresses, social security number, other government-issued identification number and telephone numbers. We will update your information as information is processed through the Site and/or new information is made available to us in an effort to keep your information current, accurate and complete. On certain sections of our Site, only persons who provide us with the requested personal information and authorize and enable certain location-verification activities will be able to purchase, license and/or apply for products, programs and services available by or through the Site and/or otherwise participate in the Site's activities and offerings (" **Products** "). Please be aware that we use geo-filtering software and services (" **Geo-location Software** ") to verify your location within the State of Georgia as required for the purchase of game Products through the Sites. The Geo-location Software collects data relevant to verify your location within the State of Georgia (" **Geo-location Data** "). 

Site usage, measurement, analytics and other data and information available to us directly or from our service providers in aggregated or other non-personalized forms or formats are outside the scope of this Privacy Policy and not subject to the collection or usage restrictions set forth herein.

### Our Use of Your Information

When we receive your personal information, we will only use it for the purposes described where it is collected, to administer the Site and/or provide Products to you through the Site and as otherwise described in this Policy. We further reserve all rights necessary to use and disclose your personal information as required and/or permitted pursuant to all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the Georgia Lottery Corporation and its Sites and Products. We will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of our organization unless (1) you expressly authorize us to do so; (2) it is necessary to allow our service providers or agents to provide Products for us or on our behalf, (3) it is necessary to allow our vendors to provide you third-party products owned or controlled by them, such as the iHOPEcard, through this Site, to provide services for such products for us or on our behalf as they relate to our Products and services, and to provide services and other products for vendor on vendor's behalf subject to additional terms and policies, (4) it is necessary in order to provide our Products to you, including in connection with the review, processing and consideration of any application for Products submitted by you, and/or award any prizes to you in connection with winning game Products, including purchaser verification, background checks, credit checks, authentication, geo-location and authorization for any orders (and contacting you when necessary), (5) subject to applicable contractual or legal restrictions, it is disclosed to entities that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other entities with whom we have joint marketing agreements, (6) it is necessary in connection with other business purposes including, without limitation, administration of this Site and/or Products offered through the Site, customer care or convenience, service quality, business management and operation, risk assessment, security, fraud and crime prevention/detection, monitoring, research and analysis, marketing, customer purchasing preferences and trends, dispute resolution, credit checking and debt collection, account maintenance and fulfillment activities, and awarding and payment of prizes, as applicable, including tax reporting and performance of other compliance and offset obligations required or permitted by law in connection therewith, (7) otherwise as we are required or permitted by law. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, as required by the Georgia Open Records Act, certain information collected through our Sites or provided by you to us through our Sites will be regarded as matters of public record and may be released by us to the public. 

Your Geo-location Data may be collected and used by us and by our third-party vendors and service providers to verify your location and, as applicable, to allow you to purchase game Products through the Sites and as required or permitted by law and/or pursuant to the Lottery's Terms of Use and this Policy. Please see our Terms of Use for additional information and terms and conditions applicable to the Geo-location Software and Geo-location Data. We reserve the right to retain a record of your Geo-location Data confirming your presence within the State of Georgia in accordance with applicable law and/or any rules, regulations, policies and procedures of or applicable to the Georgia Lottery Corporation and its Sites and Products.

If you do not agree to Our Use of Your Information above, we cannot do business with you or accept purchases of or applications for Products from you through the Site. Your continued use of this Site, registration for Players Club, application for any Product available through the Site or other offerings, or purchase of any Products sold through this Site constitutes your acceptance of this Policy. Information collected by us through the Sites is considered a corporate asset and subject to transfer, sale and assignment to any successor-in-interest in the event of a corporate reorganization, merger or sale.

### Contests, Second Chance Drawings and Other Promotions

We may offer contests and other promotions on this Site, including second-chance drawings for instant ticket customers (collectively, " **Promotions** "). These Promotions may be subject to special rules provided on relevant pages of the Site, and may require you to register via an online registration form to create a user account. If you choose to participate in these Promotions, and are eligible to do so, we may ask you for information such as your name, mailing address, email address, date of birth and telephone number. During the registration process, you may be required to choose a user name and/or password. You acknowledge and agree that we may use and rely on this password to identify you. These Promotions may also allow you to share information about these Promotions with others. We will use any information you provide to administer the Promotions, including to award prizes, report such awards to applicable tax authorities, comply with other applicable laws, rules and regulations and perform other compliance and offset obligations required or permitted by law in connection with the awarding of prizes. Subject to applicable contractual or legal restrictions, we also may use the information to communicate with you, or the other people you identify, about our Products, to allow our partners to communicate with you about the Promotions or their products and services, for other purposes disclosed to you at the point of data collection, to comply with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the Georgia Lottery Corporation and its Products and for other purposes consistent with applicable law.

### Direct Marketing Material

Subject to applicable contractual or legal restrictions, we may contact you with information on offers of new or existing products, services, offerings and upcoming events. You agree to electronic communications when you make a purchase and/or submit information for our Products online. From time to time, you may be able to indicate your preference regarding receipt of direct marketing material from a third party in your capacity as a Site user. If you do not wish to receive such information or would like to change your preference, please refer to " **Your Rights** " below.

### Your Messages

We appreciate and welcome your questions and comments about us and our Products by email at [glottery@galottery.org](mailto:glottery@galottery.org) or by telephone at 1-800-GA-Lucky (1-800-425-8259). We will share your messages with those within our organization and to applicable third-party providers who we believe are most capable of addressing your questions and comments. We may archive your message for a certain period of time or discard it once it is no longer needed.

### Your Rights

You have the right to ask in writing not to receive direct marketing material from us. If applicable, you can amend your previous preference by emailing an "unsubscribe email" to [unsubscribe@galottery.org](mailto:unsubscribe@galottery.org) or refer to our messages (including the email or other electronic communications sent to you by us) containing unsubscribe instructions. Once properly notified by you, we will take steps to stop using your information in this way or to modify your information, as applicable. Please allow us a reasonable period of time in order to satisfy your request. We note that without use of your information, we may not be able to provide you the Products or the same quality of Products you request. If you request removal of certain information from your account, then we will only retain copies of such information as necessary for us to comply with governmental orders, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, enforce any agreement you have entered into with us and as otherwise reasonably necessary for our business purposes, including compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the Georgia Lottery Corporation and its Products. The foregoing does not constitute and we do not make any representation, express, implied or statutory, all of which are hereby expressly disclaimed, that all electronic copies of your information have been destroyed. For clarity, with respect to certain Products available through the Site, our ability to remove or stop using information submitted from you that is fundamental to your ability to receive or continue to receive and/or benefit from that Product is limited by all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the Georgia Lottery Corporation and that specific Product.

You also have the right to withdraw your consent to the use of the Geo-location Software at any time by taking certain steps to discontinue our access to the Geo-location Data; however, game Products will not be available to you through the Sites. Please see our [Terms of Use](https://www.mygalottery.com/en-us/footer/trmscndtions.html) for additional information and terms and conditions applicable to the Geo-location Software and Geo-location Data.

### Use of Tools, "Cookies" and Links to Other Websites

This Site may use "cookies" or similar technology (" **Cookies** "). Cookies allow us to identify your device, but not you personally. You can set your web browser or mobile settings to refuse Cookies. However, if you do so, you may not be able to enjoy access and use all of the Products and services available to you on this Site.

If you receive our email marketing, we may tailor the information we send you unless you tell us not to. This means we may use information we hold and Cookies to identify your individual Site search behavior, location and preferences. This will enable us to send you more personalized and relevant communications. You will be given the opportunity on every personalized communication to opt-out of this personalization except in circumstances where such personalization is required for the proper administration and operation of a specific Site section or Product or required by law.

We and our third-party service providers and partners may collect information relating to analytics, customer trends and patterns and use Cookies and software tools to measure usage, session times and other analytical information. If you are making a purchase or an application for a Product, we may also use Cookies to keep track of the transaction from one area of the Site to another.

In addition to the information we collect from Cookies, we may also obtain information which you provide to us electronically - for example, when you sign up for new Product updates or when you purchase Products, or otherwise when you communicate with us. In some cases, we retain both the cookie information and/or the information you provide to us electronically - for example, to complete a transaction you requested or to keep historical records of your past transactions. In other cases, we only retain the Cookie and/or electronic information you give us if you request us to do so for your use in subsequent sessions.

An Internet Protocol address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. Similar identifiers are available for other electronic devices used to communicate in other ways. When you visit this Site, we may view the applicable device identifier (which may include the city, domain address and service provider). We use this information, as well as geo-location information, to determine the general physical location of the device, understand the general location of visitors to this Site and verify eligibility to participate in certain features and offerings of the Site. We also may use this information to enhance this Site.

Certain pages on our Sites contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow us and our third-party service providers and partners to obtain information such as the unique device identifier associated with the device that accessed or downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in Cookies set by the third-party.

For third-party products and services available to you through this Site, we may share any or all of the information we collect with such provider to assist in your receipt of and access to such products and services. In such circumstances, you may be asked to accept the terms and policies of such provider. You should read all applicable terms and policies carefully to ensure you understand how such third party may use your information.

### Children

This Site is not intended or authorized for, or designed to attract, use by any person under the age of 18. We recognize that areas of this Site are generally available for viewing by visitors to the Site; however, areas of the Site that require registration and the submission of personal information are intended solely for persons over 18. Accordingly, we do not knowingly collect information from or about children or provide services to children on this Site. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we will not knowingly collect any information from children under the age of 13. 

### Monitoring

To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, improve our products and services, provide security and enable compliance with all laws, rules, regulations, policies and procedures applicable to the Georgia Lottery Corporation and its Products, we may monitor and/or record: (1) telephone calls; and (2) transactions and activities on this Site. All recordings and other records are the sole property of the Georgia Lottery Corporation.

### Security Statement

We take reasonable steps to protect your personal information, including keeping your financial information private and safe. You acknowledge, however, that no transmission of data over the Internet or other electronic means can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, despite our efforts. Thus, while we will use and will require our applicable service providers to use commercially reasonable means consistent with general industry standards to secure information you transmit to us consistent with our legal requirements, we cannot guarantee that such information will not be intercepted by third parties.

### Visiting This Website From Outside Of The United States

If you are visiting this Site or attempting to purchase Products from outside of the United States or otherwise contacting us from outside of the United States, please be aware that your personal information may be transferred to, stored or processed in the United States, where many of the service providers and servers related to this Site are located. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to protect your privacy. Nothing in this Section is intended to expand or otherwise alter any provisions set forth or referenced in the Site [Terms of Use](https://www.mygalottery.com/en-us/footer/trmscndtions.html) limiting access to and use of the Site and Products available on or through the Site to certain locations.

### Changes to this Policy

We may change this Policy at any time. Any changes to this Policy will be posted on this Site or made available on request. The most recent version of the Policy is reflected by the version date located at the bottom of this Policy. This Policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal right in or on behalf of any party. 

### Links to Other Websites

For your convenience, we may provide links to other third-party products and services that we do not control. Additionally, our iHOPEcard providers have separate terms and privacy policies located in the [GTECH Privacy Policy](https://www.mygalottery.com/en-us/footer/gtech-pp.html) and the [Wave Crest iHOPE™ Discover® Debit Card Cardholder Agreement](https://www.mygalottery.com/en-us/footer/wcterms.html). We cannot be responsible for the terms of use or privacy practices of any websites, pages, products or services not under our control and we do not endorse any of these websites or applications, the services or products described or offered on such sites or applications, or any of the content contained on those sites or applications. Please refer to the privacy policies applicable to those third-party products and services.

### How To Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Policy, our use of your Geo-location Data or how to discontinue our access to your Geo-location Data, or if you would like to learn more about how we protect privacy, please contact us by mail at Georgia Lottery Corporation, 250 Williams Street, Suite 3000, Atlanta, Georgia 30303, or by phone at 1-800-GA-LUCKY (1-800-425-8259) or by email at [glottery@galottery.org](mailto:glottery@galottery.org).

**Privacy Policy: Last updated June 28, 2015.**
